ALMAS BAIMAGAMBETOV

WORK EXPERIENCE

Oct. 2017 - Present	PART-TIME LECTURER & MODULE LEADER IN GAME DEVELOPMENT UNIVERSITY OF BRIGHTON, UK
Ост. 2015 - Ост. 2017	Hourly-Paid Lecturer in Programming and Game Design & Development University of Brighton, UK
June 2014 - Oct. 2016	ENGLISH-RUSSIAN INTERPRETER (ZERO-HOUR CONTRACT) LLP AKTUBNIGRI, KAZAKHSTAN
Jan 2013 - Oct. 2016	In-house Programmer (Zero-Hour Contract) LLP AktubNIGRI, Kazakhstan
Ост. 2012 - Feb. 2015	(VOLUNTEER) GUEST SPEAKER AND MENTOR FOR IT STUDENTS BELLERBYS COLLEGE, UK

EDUCATION

July 2015 - Present	PHD IN COMPUTING, ENGINEERING AND MATHEMATICS THESIS: AUTOMATED VISUALIZATION OF GROUPED NETWORKS KEYWORDS: SET THEORY, GRAPH THEORY, TOPOLOGY, COMPUTATIONAL GEOMETRY & GRAPHICS, EULER DIAGRAMS UNIVERSITY OF BRIGHTON, UK	RESEARCH
Ост.2012 - July 2015	BSC IN COMPUTER SCIENCE (GAMES), UNIVERSITY OF BRIGHTON, UK FIRST CLASS HONOURS FINAL YEAR PROJECT: ANALYSIS OF SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ISSUES IN LARGE SCALE GAMES GRADE: 87% MODULES STUDIED	
SEPT. 2011 - JUNE 2012	FOUNDATION DEGREE IN IT, BELLERBYS COLLEGE, UK GRADE: 94%	
JULY 2011	ENGLISH LANGUAGE TRAINING, ST. GILES INTERNATIONAL, UK FINAL LEVEL: ADVANCED	

SCHOLARSHIPS AND CERTIFICATES

SEPT. 2015	International Research Scholarship, University of Brighton
JULY 2015	BEST FINAL YEAR DEVELOPMENT PROJECT, UNIVERSITY OF BRIGHTON
Nov. 2014	ACADEMIC MERIT BASED SCHOLARSHIP, UNIVERSITY OF BRIGHTON
Nov. 2013	ACADEMIC MERIT BASED SCHOLARSHIP, UNIVERSITY OF BRIGHTON
June 2012	TOP #1 FOUNDATION STUDENT, BELLERBYS COLLEGE
MAY 2012	BEST IT STUDENT, BELLERBYS COLLEGE

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH: FLUENT / PROFESSIONAL

KAZAKH: NATIVE RUSSIAN: NATIVE

KEY PERSONAL SKILLS

• THEORETICAL AND ANALYTICAL PROBLEM-SOLVING SKILLS

• SELF-MOTIVATED, HARD-WORKING AND INDEPENDENT

- ABILITY TO QUICKLY ADAPT TO NEW TECHNOLOGIES AND LEARNING ENVIRONMENTS
- ABILITY TO QUICKLY ESTABLISH INTER-PERSONAL COMMUNICATION
- · ABILITY TO LEAD, MANAGE AND OVERSEE DIFFERENT ASPECTS OF VARIOUS DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

TECHNICAL SKILLS

BASIC KNOWLEDGE: SQL, HTML5, CSS3, HASKELL, PYTHON, NODE.JS, SPRING,

FDD, AGILE

INTERMEDIATE KNOWLEDGE: C++, SDL2, OPENGL, JS, GIT, WIN/MAC/LINUX, LATEX

ADVANCED KNOWLEDGE: JAVA, JAVAFX, KOTLIN,

API DESIGN, GAME ENGINE DEVELOPMENT, TDD, CI, SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PRINCIPLES AND PRACTICES

INTERESTS AND ACTIVITIES

EDUCATION, TECHNOLOGY, OPEN-SOURCE, SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT, COMPUTER SCIENCE DATA VISUALIZATION, AUTOMATED GRAPHICAL LAYOUT GENERATION CHESS

RESEARCH

MAY 2017	Novel Algorithm for Euler Diagram Generation
MARCH 2017	DATA VISUALIZATION WORKSHOP
MARCH 2017	Drawing Effective Euler Diagrams
SEPT. 2016	VISUALIZATION OF GROUPED NETWORKS
June 2016	GROUPED NETWORKS AND ASSOCIATED CHALLENGES
MAY 2016	Euler Diagram Generation Techniques

BSC IN COMPUTER SCIENCE (GAMES)

GRADES

Module		CREDITS
MOBILE APPLICATION DEVELOPMENT		20
PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES, CONCURRENCY AND CLIENT SERVER COMPUTING		20
Applied Intelligent Systems		10
EMERGING GAMES TECHNOLOGIES		20
Computer Graphics Algorithms		10
Final Year Project		40

STATEMENT

I AM AN ACTIVE RESEARCHER IN THE FIELD OF AUTOMATED DIAGRAM GENERATION. I TEACH A RANGE OF THEORETICAL AND PRACTICAL COMPUTER SCIENCE MODULES TO 1ND, 2ND AND 3RD YEAR STUDENTS. I MAINTAIN FXGL, A JAVAFX GAME ENGINE. I RUN AN EDUCATIONAL YOUTUBE CHANNEL COVERING GAME AND SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT.

CONTACT DETAILS

GOOGLE+ | LINKEDIN | GITHUB | ALMASLVL@GMAIL.COM